这是第一期浓缩课程的第五讲
this is now the fifth lecture of the
condensed matter course in the first
在四个讲座中，我们研究了固体中的振动，并研究了固体中的电子
four lectures we studied vibrations in
solids and we studied electrons in
金属，我们在这些主题上学到了很多东西，但我们也开发了
metals and we learned quite a bit about
these topics but we also developed a
相当长的我们无法理解的谜题清单，我写了一个清单
rather long list of puzzles things that
we couldn't understand I wrote a list of
在上一堂课的结尾，他们中有一些是礼堂的正弦
them at the end of last lecture some of
them included the sine of the hall
系数，我们无法弄清为什么有时会有一个正弦
coefficient we couldn't figure out why
it's sometimes there's one sine
有时候，这是另一个迹象，我们也抓住了他们不合理的长期
sometimes is another sign we also had
grabbed their unreasonably long mean
索默菲尔德理论中的自由之路，我们无法理解，如果你回去
free path in Sommerfeld theory and we
couldn't understand and if you go back
在早期的迪拜理论中，还有一些我们没有想到的难题
to earlier in dubai theory there are
also some puzzles there we didn't
了解为什么我们引入了一个临时截断我，我的意思是一些
understand why it was we introduced an
ad-hoc cutoff me against I mean some
动机，但这当然是临时处方，所有这些
motivation for it but it was certainly
an ad hoc prescription and all of these
问题来自同一地点，同一地点是我们没有采取
problems stem from the same place and
the same place is that we're not taking
认真对待我们并未真正考虑的材料的微观结构
seriously the microscopic structure of
materials we're not really considering
它们是由单个原子组成的，这些原子在
that they're made up of individual atoms
and the atoms are bonded together in
非常特殊且通常是周期性的方式，因此该术语的其余部分大部分是
very particular and often periodic ways
so much of the remainder of the term is
将致力于了解微观结构材料
going to be devoted to understanding how
the microscopic structure materials
影响其宏观特性，但在这样做之前可能值得
affects its macroscopic properties but
before doing that is probably worth
备份并了解为什么原子在原子内粘在一起
backing up and understanding why it is
that the atoms stick together in the
制作材料的第一位，这使我们进入了以下领域
first place to make the materials so
this brings us to the the domain of
化学以及我们不愿承认它给我们的朋友和我们的
chemistry and as much as we hate to
admit it to both our friends and our
敌人的化学反应实际上很有趣，这很重要
enemies chemistry actually is
interesting it's a it's an important
无论是科学上的问题，还是工业上的技术问题
subject both scientifically and it's
certainly industrially technologically
而且实际上它也具有一些基本的深度，您可以
and it's actually has some fundamental
deepness to it as well and you could
当然要花三到四年学习化学甚至更长的时间
certainly spend three or four years
studying chemistry or even longer and
我们将只研究一两天，这可能就是我们所要做的全部
we're gonna study it for only a day or
two and that will probably be all we
需要知道以便继续进行下去，如果您之前有化学反应
need to know in order to go on further
now if you had chemistry before some of
如果您没有化学反应，这些东西可能会有点熟悉
these things might be a little bit
familiar if you haven't had chemistry
在这之前不是什么大问题，因为我要去的大部分
before it's maybe not so much of a
problem because most of what I'm going
介绍它是相当基本的，但是主要思想是重新考虑一些
to introduce it's fairly basic but the
main idea is to reconsider some of the
从物理学的角度看化学，似乎有些事情
chemistry from a physics perspective
some of the things that may have seemed
奇怪的是，当您第一次学习化学时，也许他们
strange when you've learned for
chemistry the first time well maybe they
这次似乎更自然一些，这将使我们有所
seemed a little bit more natural this
time through and this will give us sort
了解大部分内容的基础
of a foundation for understanding much
of what
来晚了，所以一个好的开始是认识到
comes comes later so a good place to
start is to realize that you know
化学都是基于薛定inger方程的
chemistry is all based on the
Schrodinger equation the Schrodinger
您知道的等式可以解决所有问题，并告诉您电子为何粘附
equation you know solves everything it
tells you why the electrons stick to
原子核，以及为什么原子核互相粘连等等
nuclei and why nuclei
stick to each other and so forth it's
所有简短的内部方程式，但这实际上并不是思考的一种非常有用的方法
all the short inner equation but that's
not actually a very useful way to think
因为解决薛定because方程不只一个
about things because solving the
Schrodinger equation for more than one
或两个粒子变得难以置信，并且您永远无法开发出任何一种
or two particles becomes impossibly hard
and you can never develop any sort of
直觉发生了什么，所以我们应该做的是我们应该思考
intuition of what's going on
so what we should do is we should think
关于非常简单的卡通级问题，并尝试找出
about very very simple cartoon level
problems and try to figure out what the
一般规则是化学反应，从一个好的地方开始是氢
general rules are of chemistry from that
a good place to start is with hydrogen
氢或更一般地说是氢原子，表示它的原子核为
hydrogen or more generally a hydrogenic
atom meaning that it has a nucleus of
G中的一些电荷产生Z和一个电子的原子核，
charge in G some generating nucleus
nucleus of charge Z and one electron and
您会从原子物理学课程或量子力学中记住
you'll remember from your atomic physics
courses or your quantum mechanics
当然，这个电子的本征态被许多
courses that the eigenstates of this one
electron are indexed by a number of
量子数主量子数n等于一二三，所以
quantum numbers the principal quantum
number n equals one two three and so
第四角动量量子数
forth the angular momentum quantum
number which it takes the number the
值0 1 2到n减1，这些角动量量子数为
values 0 1 2 up to n minus 1 and these
angular momentum quantum numbers are
有时称为s PDFG等，现在来自光谱符号
sometimes called s P D F G and so forth
coming from spectroscopic notation now
有人知道一个巧克力棒的PD和F代表尖锐的是s
for one chocolate bar does anyone know
that s P D and F stand for sharp is s
那让你四分之一d是分散的，是的，你快到了
that gets you a quarter d is diffuse yes
you almost there
另外两个校长有人说校长有人得到了谁是
two more principal someone said
principal someone who got it who was
有人在那边说，你还好，所以他明白了
that someone said it over there it's you
okay so he gets it so sharp principal
从光谱符号上扩散和精细，对不起，您的巧克力
diffuse and fine from spectroscopic
notations your chocolate sorry
从你下面偷了哎呀，还有人再来一块巧克力吧
stolen out from under you
gee does anyone one more chocolate bar
甚至告诉我G是什么意思，实际上什么都不是，是因为
even tell me what G is for it's not for
anything actually it's it's uh it's for
长颈鹿，除了那好吧，他们只需要再写一封信
giraffe they just need another letter
after that okay um anyway in addition to
角心态量子数M取负L到L的值，然后
the angular mental quantum numbers M
takes the values minus L to L and then
最重要的是，自旋量子数可以为正负二分之一
the spin quantum number can be plus or
minus one-half the most important thing
要跟踪的是，如果您具有电子本征态，也许应该
to keep track of is if you have s
electrons s eigenstates maybe how should
我这样说，所以我认为本征态可以容纳两个有两个
I say this so in s shell I guess of of
eigenstates can hold two has two
可能的本征态P壳，所以为什么-因为s意味着L等于零，所以
possible eigenstates P shell so why is
it - because s means L equals zero that
表示M必须等于零，但自旋可以是正负1/2，所以两个
means M has to be equal zero but the
spin can be plus or minus 1/2 so two
豌豆壳的可能性有六个，因为P表示l等于一个M
possibilities with a pea shell there are
six because P means l equals one M can
为负1 0 1为3，则自旋可以取两个值使6d
be minus 1 0 1 that's 3 and then the
spin can take two values that make 6d
给你十个，依此类推现在你拥有所有这些本征态
gives you 10 and so forth now you have
all these eigenstates in a particular
原子，然后您认为自己在其中拥有许多电子
atom and then you suppose to yourself
that you have many electrons in that
原子不仅仅是一个电子，原子我也应该大概
atom not just a single electron the atom
also I should probably should probably
给你的能量以及这些本征态的能量是-
give you the energies as well the
energies of these eigenstates are - the
如果原子核的电荷更多，则在N平方乘以Z平方摆脱berg
rid berg over N squared times Z squared
if the charge of the nucleus is more
大于1加上小改正之类的东西，例如Hyper和Hyper的罚款就好
than 1 plus small Corrections things
like fine and Hyper's fine fine
结构，但主要能量只是来自于原理量子数，所以
structure but the main energy just comes
from the principle quantum number ok so
现在你的原子中有一束电子，你需要弄清楚
now you have a bunch of electrons in
your atom and you need to figure out
这些本征态中的哪些充满电子，而哪些空着
which of these eigenstates you fill with
electrons and which ones you leave empty
有几个规则可以解决这个问题，第一个规则称为
and there's several rules for figuring
this out the first rule is known as the
阿尔贝勒原理奥夫鲍原理
alpha Belle principle Aufbau principle
基本上只是被贝壳填充
which is basically just fill by shells
因此，当您向原子中添加第一个电子时，您会在一个壳中开始并保持
so when you add the first electron to an
atom you start in one shell and you keep
填满该壳，直到填满该壳为止
filling that shell until it's filled
when you finish filling that shell you
开始填充下一个外壳，然后填充该外壳，直到
start filling the next shell and you
fill that one until it's
现在您以什么顺序装满炮弹，然后由马德隆的装满炮弹
now in what order do you fill the shells
well you fill the shelves by madelung's
像这样的肺炎法则，玛德隆氏法则
rule madelung's rule which has a nice
pneumonic like this you write out a
表1s 2s 2p 3s 3p 3d 4s 4p 4d 4f 5s等
table 1s 2s 2p 3s 3p 3d 4s 4p 4d 4f 5s
and so forth
5P博士thot，然后您以对角线的方式填写，这是第一个，这是
5p dr. thot and then you fill in this
diagonal way this one is first this is
第二，这是第三，这是第四，依此类推，这将是第五
second this is third this is fourth and
so forth and this would be fifth down
这样的方式，所以填充壳的顺序就是给您结构的方式
that way okay so this order of filling
shells is what gives you the structure
我们来看看我们的朋友，元素周期表
of the periodic table let's take a look
at our friend the periodic table oops I
看不到哦
don't see the Oh
停止停止停止停止停止停止停止停止停止好吧坚持
stop stop stop stop stop stop stop stop
stop okay hold on
现在没有男孩了，我们有一个真正的问题停下来哦
no boy now we have a real problem stop
Oh
好吧好吧，所以元素周期表让我们继续看我们是否可以得到这个
okay well okay so the periodic table
let's go on and see if we can get this
稍后开始，所以每个人都在您的笔记中
started up a little bit later so
everyone kind of note you have in your
沿着正确的方向前进，因此您首先要填充
head what it looks like right so you
start out by filling the the top row of
当一个电子充满时，其中含有氢氦的元素周期表充满
the periodic table which has hydrogen
helium in it as one electron fills fills
氢，下一个充满氦气，然后用锂开始下一行
hydrogen the next one fills helium then
you start the next row with with lithium
和铍填充第二个弹壳，然后有六个
and beryllium that fills up the second
shell then you have the next six
元素硼碳氮氧氟和氖让我再试一次
elements boron carbon nitrogen oxygen
fluorine and neon let me try this again
看看那是否能使硼氮碳Neah氟氖起作用，然后
see if that's gonna work boron nitrogen
carbon Neah fluorine neon and then
您正在填充2p外壳，依此类推，等等，然后完全填充它们
you're filling the 2p shell and so forth
and so on and you fill them at all on
所有这些顺序，并为您提供元素周期表的结构，但您
all this order and that gives you the
structure of the periodic table but you
可能会想知道自己稍等一下
might wonder to yourself well wait a
second
为什么在3d外壳之前填充4s外壳，因为
why is it that we're filling the 4s
shell before the 3d shell because
根据上面的公式，三个壳应该有较低的能量
according to that formula up there the
three shell should have lower energy
而不是四个弹壳，那么是什么赋予了我们在开始之前充满4s的权利
than the four shell and so what gives us
the right to fill up 4s before before we
填满3d，为此我们为什么要填满周期表哦，感谢上帝
fill up 3d and for that matter why are
we filling a periodic table oh thank god
所以有周期表，我们按照这个顺序填写第一个
so there's the periodic table and we
fill in this order there's a the first
给第二个壳加壳2 2's 2p 3s 3p，然后在前面加满4s
shell the second shell two 2's 2p 3s 3p
and there's 4s filling up before the
在3d之前，您可能会问得很好，为什么我们要填充2s
before the 3d you might ask the question
well why is it we're filling up 2s
在2p之前，因为根据该公式，他们有或多或少的
before 2p because according to that
formula up there they have more or less
同样的能量，所以这个问题的答案基本上是因为
the same energy so the the answer to
this question is basically because V of
R在R上不等于1，它与库仑相互作用不成比例
R is not equal to 1 over R it's not
proportional to the Coulomb interaction
很好，为什么不那么好，它不只是一个电子和一个原子核，而是一个
anymore well why not well it's not just
a single electron and a nucleus it's an
电子与原子中所有其他电子相互作用以及
electron interacting with all of the
other electrons in the atom as well as
原子核，这样电子越靠近原子核，它所看到的越多
the nucleus so as the electron gets
closer to the nucleus it sees more
原子核和更少的其他电子，它到达的距离越远
nucleus and less of the other electrons
and it gets as far as it gets farther
离开它会看到更多您可以想到的其他电子，因此拥有某种
away it sees more of the other electrons
you can think of so having some sort of
有效电位是电子与电子之间的相互作用
effective potential which is the
interaction between the electron and
其他电子的原子核和云都需要修改
both the nucleus and the cloud of the
other electrons so you need to modify
这个电位的形状有些许，如果您尝试解决这个问题或径向
the shape of this potential somewhat and
if you try to solve this or the radial
您解决的量子力学问题知道氢原子，但是您
quantum mechanics problem that you solve
you know for the hydrogen atom but you
改变这种潜力的形状，您会突然发现
change the shape of this potential
you'll all of a sudden discover that all
这些弹壳现在具有不同的能量，它们会四处移动，这就是为什么这些
these shells have different energies now
they shift around and that's why these
这些填充轨道的顺序不是您所期望的
the ordering of these filling of the
orbitals is not what you would expect
从一个简单的氢原子实际上是我们在
from just a simple hydrogen atom
actually was we're on the subject of the
与其他电子的相互作用，您可能会感到惊讶，我们可以
interaction with the other electrons you
might find it surprising that we can
甚至描述了一般电子氢的本征态
even describe the eigenstates of the
hydrogen of a general electron the same
我们可以像描述原子本征态的方式一样
way we can a general atom the same way
we can describe the eigenstates of a
氢原子，因为您知道它不仅与原子核相互作用，而且
hydrogen atom because you know it's not
just interacting with the nucleus it's
也与所有其他电子相互作用，但原因或多或少
interacting with all the other electrons
as well but the reason more or less you
可以这样做是因为您可以治疗自己以外的所有其他电子
can do this is because you can treat all
of the other electrons besides yourself
它只是球形的云，所以还是球形的
it's just some sort of spherical cloud
so it's still sort of a spherical
问题，所以它遵循或多或少相同的规则，您仍然可以枚举
problem so it follows more or less the
same rules and you can still enumerate
可能的本征态也一样，所以这是一般结构
the possible eigenstates in the same way
okay so this is a the general structure
元素周期表的内容，现在我们可以继续探讨化学键
of the periodic table and we can now
move on to asking about chemical bonds
在元素周期表中的原子之间，好了，玛德琳的法则充满了
between the atoms in the periodic table
okay there's filling up Madeleine's rule
所以有很多不同类型的绑定，有一个图表看起来像
so there's a bunch of different types of
bonding there's a chart that looks like
这本书中的告诉您五种不同类型的
this in the in the in the book which
tells you five different types of
键合离子共价金属分子氢及其一些
bonding ionic covalent metallic
molecular hydrogen and some of their
属性及其原因是值得熟悉的
properties and what causes them it's
probably worth familiarizing yourself
借助其网上图表，您今天知道我们将尝试涵盖我们的
with its chart over the net you know
today we're going to try to cover our
离子ik和共价其他类型，我们稍后将在
ion ik and covalent the other types
we'll do a little bit later on in the in
讲座系列，所以您知道基本的基本事实在您身上
the lecture series so the the you know
the basic basic facts are on this you
应该知道这些，但是今天我们将从最简单的类型开始
should probably know these but we will
just start today with the simplest type
离子键的键合
of bonding which is ionic bonding
离子键的原理基本上是电子是
and the principle of an ionic bond is
basically that an electron is
从一个原子从一个原子转移到另一个原子，然后
transferred from one atom from one atom
atom to another to another and then the
离子吸引，然后离子吸引，所以这种反应是一种
ions attract then ions attract so the
kind of the kind of a sort of reaction
我们可以拥有的是一个钠原子加一个氯原子，一个电子是
that we we can have is a sodium atom
plus a chlorine atom an electron is
从钠转移到氯，所以我们得到钠加
transferred from the sodium to the
chlorine so we get sodium plus plus
氯减去，然后我有两个带电物种，它们吸引每个
chlorine minus and then now I have two
charged species and they attract each
其他形式的氯化钠听起来很容易，可能是最简单的方法
other in the form sodium chloride sounds
easy enough probably the easiest way to
跟踪这种反应或评估这种分析
keep track of this kind of reaction or
to evaluate this kind of analyze this
反应的类型是考虑与每个步骤相关的能量，因此
type of reaction is to think about the
energies associated with each step so
一种能量是电离能
one piece of the energy is the
ionization energy the ionization which
是将电子从钠原子上拉出来以产生钠离子的能量，
is the energy to pull the electron off
the sodium atom to make a sodium ion and
一个电子，所以您从钠原子中性开始，将电子拉开
an electron so you start with the sodium
atom neutral you pull the electron apart
从中取出无穷大，钠离子无限远
from it and put it out infinity and the
sodium ion infinitely far away at
无穷大，这将是能量上的差异，拉动
infinity and this will be the difference
in energies what's required to pull the
离开原子的电子还有所谓的电子亲和力
electron off the atom there's also
what's known as the electron affinity
当您将电子放到
which is the energy that you get back
when you put the electron on the
氯原子生成氯离子，然后最后一块被称为
chlorine atom to make a chlorine ion and
then the last piece is known as the
内聚能或键能
cohesive energy or the bonding energy
当您将钠离子和
which is the energy you get out when you
put together the sodium ion and the
氯离子得到氯化钠还可以吗
chlorine ion
to get sodium chloride okay so the total
该反应的能量预算是离子，您返回的电离能
energy budget for this reaction is e ion
the ionization energy you get back the
亲和能与电子的亲和力，则返回内聚能，
affinity energy the electron affinity
and you get back the cohesive energy and
如果总Delta e小于零，如果Delta e小于零，则您
if the total Delta e is less than zero
if Delta e is less than zero then you
得到一个反应，然后它就会反应
get a reaction then it reacts the
reaction goes towards now there's a
关于这种说法的一些警告，第一个警告是，如果
couple of caveats about about this kind
of argument the first caveat is that if
你是化学家，你不可避免地在谈论吉布斯自由能，而不是
you're chemists you are inevitably
talking about Gibbs free energies rather
不仅仅是能量，而吉布斯自由能量的原因是因为你
than just energies and the reason it's
Gibbs free energies is because you're
在有限的温度（可能是室温）下进行实验
doing your experiment at finite
temperature probably room temperature
和有限的压力，您的房间压力，我们会认为，就像我们在做
and finite pressure your room pressure
we're gonna think just as if we're doing
一切都在零温度，零压力下进行，所以我们可以考虑一下
everything at zero temperature zero
pressure so we can just think about
能量，但第二件事应该或多或少是同一件事
energies but it's more or less the same
thing the second thing one should be
警告您是否正在读书是凝聚力或粘合一词
warned about if you're reading books is
that the word cohesive energy or bonding
每个人在不同的书中以不同的方式使用能量
energy is used in several different
senses in different books everyone
同意凝聚力或键合能量是放两件东西的能量。
agrees that a cohesive energy or bonding
energy is the energy to put two things
在一起，但并非所有人都同意这两个东西应该是什么，所以他们会
together but not everyone agrees what
those two things should be so they'll
谈论氯化钠的内聚能，一些书会告诉你
talk about the cohesive energy for
sodium chloride and some books will tell
您，整个Delta e是凝聚力，有些书会告诉您
you that the whole Delta e is the
cohesive energy and some books will tell
您，凝聚力只是将钠放在一起的能量
you that the cohesive energy is just the
energy for putting together the sodium
离子和氯离子，因此您会得到两个不同的结果
ion and the chlorine ion so you'll get
two different results depending on it
是否要计算整个Delta e并称其为绑定
whether you're accounting the whole
Delta e and calling that the bonding
能量，或者您只是在谈论将两个离子放在一起的能量
energy or if you're just talking about
the energy to put together the two ions
这是另一个警告，最后一个警告是您得到的结果
so that's another warning the last
warning is that the results that you get
结合能量的方法会截然不同，具体取决于您在说什么
for bonding energy will be extremely
different depending if you're talking
关于摄取一钠离子和一氯离子
about taking one ion of sodium and one
ion than chlorine and putting them
一起制成氯化钠分子，或者如果您正在谈论
together to make a sodium chloride
molecule or if you're talking about
拿很多，把它们放在一起，
taking lots of them and putting them
together to make a whole big chunk of
氯化钠，其原因是因为您知道您的钠原子
sodium chloride and the reason for this
is because you know your sodium atom if
它要么与一种氯结合，要么与许多不同的氯结合
it's either bonded to one chlorine or
it's bonded to a lot of different
氯将是完全不同的能量，具体取决于多少东西
chlorines it will be a totally different
energy depending on how many things
您与之紧密相连，这是另一件事
you're bonded to
so that's another thing to keep in mind
要小心，所以在这组试图追踪的能量中
to be careful about okay so in this set
of energies that were try to keep track
可能最容易理解的是
of probably the easiest thing to
understand is the bonding energy of the
内聚能，也称为马德隆能或库仑能
cohesive energy also known as the
madelung energy or the Coulomb energy
因为这种库仑能量基本上就是库仑
because this Coulomb energy is basically
just it's basically just the Coulomb
系统中相关离子之间的两个能量之间的关系
energy between the two between the
relevant ions in your in your system so
在I和J之间的4个PI epsilon零距离上，我不等于j Qi QJ
i not equal to j Qi QJ over 4 PI epsilon
nought distance between the I and J so
Qi是离子上的电荷，这就是离子J，所以如果我有一个
Qi is the charge on ion
this is charged ion J so if I have a
一堆-如果我-如果我有两个，我在JI上就照常服用库仑
bunch - if I - I on J I just take its
usual the usual Coulomb if I have two
离子带正电荷的女人带负电荷的我只是总结
ions one with positive charge woman
negative charge I'm just summing up the
这些离子之间通常的库仑能获得内聚能，这是
usual Coulomb energy between those ions
to get the cohesive energy now this is a
表达键合能量或获得的能量的绝佳方法
perfectly good way to express the the
bonding energy or the energy you get by
把这两种电荷带到一起，但是很明显
taking these two charge species and
bringing them together but it obviously
实际上，对于大多数离子固体它也相当准确
and actually it's fairly accurate as
well for most ionic solids gives you a
很好地估计了由此获得的内聚能的数量
very good estimate of the the amount of
cohesive energy you get by this
定义，所以您只需要知道这些离子之间的距离
definition and so all you need to know
is how far apart those ions are and you
知道你有多少键合能量当然会有一点问题
know how much bonding energy you got of
course there's a little bit of a problem
这个表达式，如果带上
with this expression and that is it goes
to minus infinity if you bring the
钠或离子，然后氯离子非常接近，这显然是
sodium or ion then the chlorine ion
extremely close and that's obviously
没有任何意义，所以这里发生的实际情况是R IJ
doesn't make any sense so what's really
happening here like this this is a R IJ
在两个原子之间，这是能量，所以这是R上的1曲线
for between the two atoms and here's the
energy so this is the 1 over R curve
您期望的库仑相互作用和获得的实际物理能量
that you expect for Coulomb interaction
and the actual physical energy you get
看起来像是R上方的1看起来像是R上方的1，然后在某个时候它突然射出
looks like 1 over R looks like 1 over R
and then at some point it shoots off way
直到无穷大，所以这是实际的，所以如果您知道2之间的距离
up to infinity so this is actual so if
you know the distance between the the 2
亚当斯（Adams）就是您的兽医，只需将这种能量即库仑
Adams's you have a vet just by taking
this energy here which is the Coulomb
预测它非常接近那里的实际结合能，因为
prediction it's extremely close to the
actual bonding energy there because you
因为射击非常快，所以是什么原因导致
because the shoot-off is extremely rapid
so what's causing this shoot off to
当你开始推动两个原子时，无穷远真的非常接近
infinity well when you start pushing two
atoms really close really close together
你意识到他们不只是点收费了，他们将要开始
you realize they're not just point
charges anymore they're gonna start to
重叠它们的轨道将开始重叠宝利排除原理是
overlap their orbitals are gonna start
to overlap Pauli exclusion principle is
将要进入游戏，因为您也尝试放置两个
going to get into the game because
you're trying to put two too you know
一处电子太多，能量就非常非常猛烈地射出
too many electrons in one place and the
energy just shoots right off very very
速度非常快，但就目前而言，至少库仑估算值仍然是
very rapidly but right here by the
minimum the Coulomb estimate is still a
很好地估计了内聚能，因此几乎所有东西
pretty good estimate of the cohesive
energy so that's pretty much everything
我们现在需要了解内聚能，电离又如何
we need to know about the cohesive
energy now what about the ionization
能量和电子亲和势能很好地电离能或电子
energy and electron affinity energies
well the ionization energy or electron
亲和能与原子中的能级有关
affinity energy have to do with the
energy levels in the atoms and in order
弄清楚我们真的​​需要解决那些的薛定inger方程
to figure that out we really need to
solve the Schrodinger equation of those
原子，你知道一个电子和一些有效的电势与
atoms and you know an electron and some
effective potential which has to do with
原子核以及所有其他电子，这是一个难题
the nucleus and also all of the other
electrons it's kind of a hard problem
但即使我们不打算实际求解较短的方程
but even though we're not going to
actually solve the shorter equation
有些趋势很容易跟踪，所以您知道
there's some trends which are pretty
easy to keep track of so this you know
如果您已经完成了化学反应，您可能已经知道了，但是这个图
if you've done chemistry you probably
know this already but the this plot this
元素周期表的图片向您展示了大的电子亲和力和
picture of the periodic table shows you
where the large electron affinities and
大电离能还是小电离能
the large ionization energies or small
ionization energies are it's also down
在这里，小电离能在这个角落被降低了，所以
here so the small ionization energies
are sort of down in this corner and so
污点的大小是最小的电离能是多少
the size of the splotch is how big the
ionization energy the smallest one being
你知道铯或在这里，大的电离能在上升
you know cesium or francium down here
and the large ionization energies way up
在氦气中的稀有气体中，电子亲和力却相反
here in the noble gases in helium
electron affinities go the other way
除了基本没有电子的稀有气体
with the exception of the noble gases
which have essentially no electron
亲和力最高的电子亲和力在此角上方
affinity the highest electron affinities
are way over here in this corner up by
氟，氯和溴在右侧，因此如果您想要
fluorine and chlorine and bromine over
on the right-hand side so if you want a
好的离子固体，您需要什么，您知道离子反应是您需要
good ionic solid what you need you know
an ionic reaction is you need to be able
轻松地将电子从一个物种中拉出，然后您想得到一个
to easily pull the electron off of one
species and then you want to get out a
大量的能量用于其他方面，因此您需要小的电离
lot of energy for putting it on the
other so you want a small ionization
能量和大的电子亲和力很好很好
energy and a large electron affinity so
good so good
离子性固体就像是您知道氯是氟化钠things
ionic solids are things like you know
chlorine is sodium fluoride rubidium
从这里经过的氯化物与从那里经过的物质捆绑在一起
chloride things from way over here bound
together with things from way over there
现在化学家对此表示，电子壳是原子的
now chemists have an expression for this
that a shell of electrons an atomic
壳要被填充，所以如果您有一个被填充的壳加上一个电子，例如
shell wants to be filled so if you have
a shell filled plus one electron like
您将在第一列中在3秒内钠具有一个电子
you would have in this first column
sodium has a one electron in the 3s
壳钾在4s壳中有一个电子，壳很容易被拉出
shell potassium has one electron in the
4s shell that shell is easily pulled off
因为当外壳完全填满时，它是最快乐的
because the shell is most happy when
it's exactly filled
类似地，氟是一种填充物，因此它具有高电子
similarly fluorine it's one short of
being filled so it has a high electron
它想被填补的亲和力，所以我们能了解一点他们主要是
affinity it wants to be filled so can we
understand a little bit they're mostly
右边的填充壳，它们具有很高的电子亲和力，
filled shells on the on the right and
they have high electron affinity and
高电离能，左侧则是小电离能
high ionization energy and on the Left
it's small ionization energy in small
电子亲和力，所以我们可以通过某种物理方式理解为什么
electron affinities so can we understand
in some physical way why this is
实际上，弄清楚为什么这至少可以使我们粗略了解并不是很困难
actually it's not too hard to figure out
why that is at least roughly we can make
它的卡通图片，让我们尝试通过观察钠来弄清楚
a cartoon picture of it so let's try to
figure it out from looking at sodium so
钠它有，如果你在这张桌子上看，它有11个元素周期表
sodium it has I'll let it's if you look
on this table a periodic table it has 11
电子是它的第11个元素，所以看起来像是具有原子核的是什么
electrons its 11th element so what is
what does it look like it has a nucleus
的电荷加上11加11的原子核，然后我们得到
of charged plus 11 plus 11 in the
nucleus and then then we have what we
在1和2的壳中有10个电子，因此我们将绘制1s和
have 10 electrons in the 1 and 2's
shells so we'll draw a picture of 1s and
2s对不起和2p，在1s 2s 2p壳中，我们让10个电子与
2s sorry and 2p and in the 1s 2s 2p
shells we have a let 10 electrons with a
负负10的电荷，那么我们的3s外壳中有1个电子
charge of minus minus 10 then we have
this 1 electron in the 3s shell out here
所以这是3s外壳中的1个电子，如果您是1个电子
so this is 1 electron out here in the 3s
shell and to that 1 electron if you
想象自己是一个电子，你实际上有多少核电荷
imagine yourself being that one electron
how much nuclear charge do you actually
很好地看到总核电荷，您将看到这个电子看到Z等于1
see well the total nuclear charge you
would see this electron sees Z equals 1
为什么好，因为其中的这10个电子或多或少地被屏蔽了
why well because these 10 electrons
inside of it are more or less screening
那是原子核中的正电荷，所以它看到的电荷只有加1，所以如果我们
that's positive charge in the nucleus so
it sees a charge of only plus 1 so if we
想用我们的氢天鹰座来找出
wanted to
use our hydrogen aquila to figure out
束缚能，我们可以说束缚能是burg乘以1
the binding energy we would say that the
binding energy is a rid burg times one
在C上平方，这是一个3 s除以三个平方N平方
squared over the C this is a three s
divided by three squared N squared
现在楼下的这种结合能电离能有点
downstairs now this binding energy
ionization energy is a little bit of an
低估了3s电子的实际结合结合能
underestimate of the actual binding
binding energy of the 3s electron and
其原因是因为有时3s电子越来越靠近
the reason for this is because sometimes
that 3s electron gets closer to the
并意识到实际上这不是+1的电荷，而是一个加号
nucleus and realizes that in fact it's
not a charge of +1 it's actually a plus
电荷大于+1，因此约束范围比此估算值还要小
charge bigger than +1 so it's bound a
little bit tighter than this estimate
会告诉我们好的，但是基本上您知道某种程度的近似
would would tell us okay but basically
you know at some level of approximation
就像1个电子束缚在一个电荷上确实有意义
it's like 1 electron bound to just one
charge does that make sense yeah okay
现在让我们看一下氟，而不是地板。
now let's look at fluorine instead
floorings a little more complicated
氟，这是第九个元素，几乎被填充以显示出什么
fluorine it's the ninth element right
over here almost filled to show so what
是什么是氟很好吗，所以我们的核带有电荷
is the what is fluorine see well okay so
we have the nucleus with a charge of
加9，然后我们将1s壳放在此处1s凝胶中，该凝胶可能会充电
plus nine and then we have the 1s shell
down here 1s gel which has might charge
减去两个，然后在两个壳中，我们有七个电子在这里
of minus two and then in the two shell
we have seven electrons out here take it
到一二三四五五六七七电子现在假设你是
to one two three four five six seven
seven electrons now suppose you're and
它们或多或少处于相同的半径，因为它们都在两个壳中，因此
they're more or less at the same radius
because they're all in the two shell so
假设您是电子，您看到的是Z的电荷等于
suppose you're this electron what do you
see you see a charge of Z equals well
也许您会看到加上七个，因为这里的这些电子没有屏蔽
maybe you see plus seven because these
electrons here aren't screening the
核，所以您只看到加9减两个现在加7有点
nucleus so you only see plus 9 minus two
now plus seven is a little bit of an
高估您，您将获得摆脱困境的能量7
over estimate you would you would then
get a binding energy of a rid burg seven
平方，让我们看，这是两个电子，所以超过两个
squared over let's see so this is a two
electron out here so it's over two
平方这个电子的主量子数平方这是一个巨大的
squared the principle quantum number
squared of this electron this is a huge
高估了氟中的实际结合能，因为有时
over estimate of the actual binding
energy in fluorine because sometimes
这些电子确实会进入该电子内部并更好地屏蔽核
these electrons do get inside of this
electron and screen the nucleus better
比我们在这里估计的要多，但是您仍然看到有一个很好的理由
than we would estimate here but still
you see that there's a very good reason
为什么它是一个几乎装满的炮弹，看到一个大核弹，一个几乎空
why it is an almost filled shell sees a
big nuclear charge and an almost empty
炮弹看到一个小的核弹，所以这是为什么
shell sees a small nuclear charge
so this is behind the origin of why it
是我们有这个卡通短语，一个几乎充满的贝壳想要成为
is that we have this this cartoon phrase
that an almost filled shell wants to be
填充，几乎要清空的填充壳想要清空，这会使
filled and an almost empty fill shell
wants to be emptied does that make some
感觉是的是的是的，好吧，所以这基本上是一个问题
sense yes yes yeah okay all right so
it's basically an issue of how well
屏幕上的核是这样，这给了我们很好的画面
screen the nucleus is so this gives us a
pretty good picture of what's going on
在离子键内，电子数量多少有差异
within ionic bonds there a differences
in how much the electrons are how much
原子想要有一个多余的电子或想要放弃另一个电子，
the atoms want to have an extra electron
or want to give up another electron and
所以如果你有一个原子如果你有一个原子如钾和一个原子如
so if you have an atom if you have an
atom like potassium and an atom like
氟钾很乐意放弃其电子氟
fluorine the potassium is happy to give
up its electron the fluorine wants to
得到一样的额外电子，你得到两个离子，然后离子被吸引，所以它是一个
get that alike extra electron you get
two ions the ions then attract so it's a
离子键的理想情况，但是您在两个键之间也有键
great picture of ionic bonding however
you also have bonding between two
在两个原子之间需要电子的电子
electrons that want between two atoms
that want the electrons just as much as
彼此之间，例如，两个氧原子之间会相互键合
it each other for example Oh to two
oxygen atoms will bond with each other
当然，他们想要电子彼此一样多，所以这是
and of course they want the electrons
just as much as each other so this is
给我们带给他们所谓的共价键共价键的图片
give brings us to the picture of what
they call covalent bonding covalent
没关系，有一个化学家有这张共价键的图片
bonds which is okay there's a chemists
have this picture of covalent bonds
他们喜欢说原子将共享电子，并且
which they like to say that the atoms
will share an electron and because
他们正在共享将原子结合在一起的电子，现在我们可以理解
they're sharing electrons that binds the
atoms together now can we understand a
从物理学上好一点点，这就是共享的意义
little bit better from physics what it
is that we mean by this that sharing
电子将原子结合在一起，因此有一个很好的画面
electrons binds atoms together so
there's a nice picture of this which
基本上只来自盒子物理中的粒子，可以放在这里
basically comes from just particle in a
box physics all right put it over here
盒子中的一个粒子，我们将分析氢，然后氢进入
particle in a box in box and we're gonna
analyze hydrogen plus hydrogen goes to
氢也只是基于我们对盒子中粒子的了解，我现在是什么
hydrogen too just based on what we know
about particle in a box now what am I
谈论当我谈论氢原子是粒子盒时，让我们
talking about when I'm talking about a
hydrogen atom being a particle box let's
在这里画一个小盒子，这个盒子应该代表了
draw a little box here that box is
supposed to represent the attraction to
原子核，所以氢原子基本上是电子与
the nucleus so a hydrogen atom is
basically it's electron bound to the
原子核好吧，这不是完全一样，除非我们是盒子，但还是有一定的约束力
nucleus so okay it's not exactly unis
we're box but it's still some binding
通过原子核，所以我们将电子放到盒子里，给她一个盒子
through the nucleus so we'll put our
electron in our box and give her a box a
L和那个盒子中电子的氢的基态能量
size L and the ground state energy of
the hydrogen of the electron in that box
L的大小是h-bar平方，pi大于2m，l平方，现在我们有另一个
of size L is h-bar squared over 2m pi
over l squared now we have another
氢原子在这里，所以我们给他一个盒子L，他的能量H
hydrogen atom here so we'll give him a
box size L and he has the same energy H
当我们有H 2时，在2m ah pi上平方的平方根pi在l平方上平方的平方现在在这里
bar squared over 2m ah pi over l squared
now over here when we have H 2 we get a
更大的盒子，也许是2 L的氢分子，那是什么，所以我们
bigger box maybe a size 2 L for the
hydrogen molecule and what are the so we
对这里较大的盒子和基态具有基波函数
have a ground state wave function for
the bigger box here and the ground state
波函数是能量H bar平方2m PI平方2 l平方
wave function is an energy H bar squared
over 2m PI over 2 l squared which is
当然，我们必须降低2个电子在这个基态波中
lower of course we have to put 2
electrons in this ground state wave
现在可以运行，但是我们可以这样做，因为有2次旋转，我们发现
function now but we can do that because
there are 2 spins and we discover that
等式的这一边低于这两个等式的总和，所以
this side of the equation is lower than
the sum of these two equations so what's
这里发生的是我们允许电子波
going on here what's going on here is
that we're allowing the electron wave
功能从局限在这里扩展到局限在
function to spread out from being
confined here and confined here to being
在这里不那么受限制，通过让wave函数展开，我们降低了
less confined here and by letting the
wave function spread out we're lowering
它的能量，这就是您知道海森堡不确定性而使Delta X
its energy this is just you know
Heisenberg uncertainty you make Delta X
ΔP越大，ΔP越小，动力学就越低
bigger Delta P gets smaller with smaller
Delta P you can have a lower kinetic
能量，所以通过散布波函数，可以降低动能
energy so by spreading out the wave
function you lower the kinetic energy
现在我们可以考虑使用氦气做同样的事情，我们将看到
now we can consider the same thing with
helium and we'll see that actually
氦气有些不同，所以氦气有一个盒子，你有一个
something is very different about helium
so helium you have a box you have your
基态波函数，这里有两个电子
ground state wave function and you have
two electrons in it here again a box
基态波函数在其中放了两个电子，然后问题是
ground state wave function put two
electrons in it and then the question is
现在可以去氦气了吗2现在有一个更大的盒子，我们可以接地
does it go to helium two okay now here
we have a bigger box we get a ground
状态波函数我们可以在其中放入两个电子然后我们必须开始
state wave function we can put two
electrons in it then we have to start
也填充了激发波函数，因为我们填充了最低的
filling up an excited wave function as
well because we filled the lowest the
基波函数我们也必须填补这个家伙，现在我们不
ground state wave function we have to
fill this guy as well and now we're not
如果我什么都没得到
gaining so much matter if I'm not
getting any
完全是因为我们不仅必须填充最低能量状态
at all because we had to as well as
filling the lowest energy state we have
填充较高的能量状态以及较低的能量状态被称为
to fill a higher energy state as well
the lower energy state is known as the
键合轨道键合轨道和高能态被称为
bonding orbital bonding orbital and the
higher energy state was known as the
反粘结轨道，所以通常我们的粘结轨道
antibonding orbital
so generally bonding orbitals our ones
其能量低于原始波函数和反键z'为
whose energy is lower than the original
wave functions and anti-bonding z' are
高于或等于原始波函数，所以这就是为什么氦非常
higher or equal to the original wave
functions so this is why I helium very
大概是为什么氦不结合而氢能结合的原因
roughly why it is that helium doesn't
bond but hydrogen does now this is
显然非常卡通化，但是我们可以通过使用所谓的
obviously very cartoonish but we can do
a better job by using what's known as
分子轨道理论分子轨道或原子轨道理论原子轨道
molecular orbital Theory molecular or
atomic orbital Theory Tomic orbital
理论也称为紧密结合理论也称为线性结合
Theory also known as tight binding
Theory also known as linear lcao lcao
等于
which equals linear combination of
现在我想如果你最后走原子路线的话
atomic orbitals of atomic orbitals now I
think if you took the atomic course last
学期，您甚至可能已经完成了此计算，我们将再次进行
term you may have even done this
calculation and we're gonna do it again
但是我们会比上学期做得更简单，我之所以成为
but we're gonna do it simpler than you
did it last term and the reason I'm
简化它是为了更容易看到潜在的物理原理，我们
simplifying it is so it's easier to see
the physics underlying okay and we're
我们将在稍后的部分中使用其中一些技术
going to use sort of we're going to use
some of these techniques later on in the
术语，使它们尽可能简单是一件好事，所以我们要做的第一件事是
term so it's good to make them as simple
as possible so the first thing we do is
我们假设有两个分别位于r1和r2的原子核，哎呀，所以我
we imagine having two nuclei of
positions r1 and r2 and oops okay so I
应该告诉您我们正在分析哪个问题，我们将这样做
should tell you which problem we're
analyzing right we're gonna do the so
我们要看的问题是看h2 plus，所以这是两个质子
the problem we're gonna look at look at
look at h2 plus so this is two protons
一个电子，两个质子和一个电子，我想你看着这个
and one electron two protons and one
electron I think you looked at this
上学期前的问题好了，所以我们要去看看
problem before last term okay so we're
going to see
允许该电子2d定位在两个原子核之间
allowing this electron 2d localize
between the two the two nuclei is going
降低其能量，从而在两个原子核之间形成一个键
to lower its energy and therefore form a
bond between the two nuclei now the
我们要做的第一件事就是使用天生的奥本海默
first thing we're gonna do is we're
going to use born-oppenheimer
近似于天生的奥本海默J罗伯特·奥本海默是
approximation born-oppenheimer J robert
Oppenheimer was the father of the
美国债券炸弹项目不是债券项目，麦克斯·伯恩（Max Born）我们已经讨论过了
American bond bomb project not bond
project and Max Born we've discussed him
已经是量子力学和奥利维亚之父之一
already father one of the fathers of
quantum mechanics and Olivia
牛顿·约翰的祖父只有一块巧克力棒，有人知道吗
newton-john's grandfather for one
chocolate bar does anyone know what
奥利维亚·牛顿·约翰（Olivia Newton-John）的热门歌曲是我给你的提示
Olivia newton-john's biggest hit song
was I'll give you a hint it has
与这个问题有关，我们正在研究是的，他说
something to do with this subject we're
studying yeah yeah who said that the
同样的人好吧，你这个很好，身体很好，十周
same person okay you get this one all
right very good physical yeah ten weeks
仍然是第一名，所以天生的奥本海默近似是
at number one okay anyway so the
born-oppenheimer approximation is
基本上固定r1和r2固定原子核的位置并使电子移动
basically fix r1 and r2 fix the position
of the nuclei and let the electron move
没关系，因为原子核非常重，它们会移动得非常快
and that's okay because the nuclei are
extremely heavy and they would move very
缓慢地移动，因此电子可以非常快地到达其本征态
slowly so the electron can come to its
eigenstate very quickly and you know and
那么您可以将所有放置在核子上并寻找
then you can sort of rece all that
wherever you put the nuclei and look for
只要原子核具有尽可能低的能量，那么我们写一个
wherever the nuclei have their lowest
possible energy so then we write a
哈密​​顿量哈密顿量为我们的电子P平方超过2m加上相互作用
Hamiltonian Hamiltonian for our electron
P squared over 2m plus the interaction
与第一个原子核的库仑相互作用加库仑相互作用
the Coulomb interaction with the first
nucleus plus the Coulomb interaction
第二个核，其中V在这里V是通常的负V平方超过4 PI
with the second nucleus where V here V
is the usual minus V squared over 4 PI
epsilon n等于R减R等等，我将其缩写为
epsilon naught R minus R one so forth
I'm going to abbreviate this thing as
这个项是K代表动能，这个项是V 1代表与动能相互作用
this term is K for kinetic energy this
term is V 1 for interaction with the
第一个原子核现在是V 2，用于与第二个原子核相互作用
first nucleus this term is V 2 for
interaction with the second nucleus now
这是一个很难的问题，因为两个原子核都存在，但这会
this is a hard problem because there's
both because of both nuclei but it would
如果我们丢掉一个原子核，假装它不存在，那就简单得多
好吧，让我们首先解决这个问题，然后我们可以让K加V 1为
okay so let's solve that that problem
first so we can then have K plus V 1 as
我们的哈密顿量，我们称本征态一
our Hamiltonian
and we'll call the eigenstate one
epsilon不是一个，那么这个问题的答案到底是什么？
你知道它在原子核上或原子核上的氢原子，所以一个是基态
hydrogen atom you know it's on on or on
nucleus one so one is the ground state
如果您喜欢，原子核上的电子之一就是S壳中的电子
of the electron on nucleus one the
electron in the S shell if you like you
可以对两个做相同的事情，所以这是如果我们只有两个原子核
can do the same thing for two so this is
if we only have nucleus two we would get
第二核的本征态，所以我可以画这些，所以这是我们的一个
an eigenstate on nucleus two so I can
draw these if I want so here's our one
这是我们的两个，那么电子将具有波函数
here's our two then there would be a
wave function here of the electron
坐在那里，好像这个家伙不在那里，然后会有一波潮
sitting there as if this guy weren't
there and then there would be a wave
那里有两个人坐在那里，好像这个家伙不在那里一样
function there two sitting there as if
this guy weren't there is that clear so
这两个状态是我正在考虑的两个原子轨道上的电子
the two states the two atomic orbitals
I'm thinking about is the electron on
绕一号核运动，好像两个核根本不存在，电子在
orbit on nucleus one as if nucleus two
are not there at all and the electron on
核2好像核1根本不在那儿很好很好所以
nucleus two as if a nucleus one we're
not there at all good good yeah okay so
您也可以将一和二视为本征态
you can also think about one and two as
being the eigenstates if the two
两个原子核的轨道相距很远，在这种情况下，
orbitals of the two nuclei taken very
very far apart in which case you have
电子位于两种原子的轨道上的两种可能性
two possibilities the electron sits on
orbital one on nucleus one or the
电子位于两个原子核上，我们期望发生的是
electron sits on nucleus two and what we
expect is going to happen is that when
我们将它们结合在一起，将有一个较低的能量状态
we bring them together there's going to
be a lower energy state the bonding
电子离域在两个原子核之间的状态
state where the electron delocalized is
between the two between the two nuclei
并且还可能有一个反键态反键，能量更高
and there may also be an antibonding
state antibonding which is higher energy
当我们将它们组合在一起时，化学家经常使用这种图表
when we bring them together this kind of
diagram is used a lot by chemists it's
称为分子轨道图分子轨道图
known as a molecular orbital diagram
molecular orbital diagram which tries to
开始移动物体时跟踪本征态发生了什么
keep track of what happens to the
eigenstates when you start moving things
一起或分开好吧，我们如何才能很好地解决这个问题，
together or apart alright so how are we
going to solve this problem well we're
用试波函数来做它
going to do it with the trial
wavefunction a variational trial
wavefunction wavefunction，我相信您已经研究了变分
wavefunction wavefunction
and I believe you've studied variational
之前的消息，因此我们将要使用的wave函数的形式为Phi 1
message before so the wave function
we're going to use is of the form Phi 1
1乘Phi 2乘2，我们将尝试找到最佳系数
times 1 plus Phi 2 times 2 and we're
gonna try to find the best coefficients
Phi 1和Phi 2会尽可能降低能量，这是
Phi 1 and Phi 2 which will lower the
energy as much as possible okay this is
您尝试获得最接近地面的变分原理
the variational principle you try to get
the best approximation to the ground
可以通过任意改变系数来表示状态，现在可以
state as you can by varying the
coefficients arbitrarily okay now this
实际上将方法的名称命名为方法的线性组合名称
actually gives the method its name the
name of the method linear combination of
我们正在做的原子轨道就是原子轨道
atomic orbitals that's exactly what
we're doing these are the atomic
轨道，我们正在对它们进行线性组合，好吧，这也众所周知
orbitals and we're making a linear
combination of them okay it's also known
紧密结合，因为电子坐在轨道1上，我们认为
as tight binding because the electron
sitting on orbital 1 we think of it at
我们认为核1与核1紧密结合
nucleus 1 we think it is tightly bound
to nucleus 1 and this one is tightly
绑定到原子核2，然后我们对两者之一进行线性组合
bound to nucleus 2 and then we make some
linear combination of those two one of
人们真正喜欢这种分析问题的方法的原因是
the reasons people really like this
method of analyzing problems is because
您实际上可以通过以下方法使近似值越来越精确
you can you can actually make the
approximation more and more accurate by
越来越多的东西添加到右侧
adding more and more things to the
right-hand side with more and more
变化的参数，所以不仅仅是跟踪两种可能性
variational parameters so instead of
just keeping track of two possibilities
电子在地核1的基态上处于轨道一
the electron is on orbital one on the
ground state of nucleus 1 in ground
核2的状态您也可以开始添加系数等
state of nucleus 2 you can start also
adding coefficients and other possible
表示电子可以在原子核1的轨道之一上处于激发态
states the electron can be in excited
States on on orbital one of nucleus 1
在原子核2上激发态，并且你建立了越来越大的基础
excited States on nucleus 2 and you make
a bigger and bigger basis set and as you
使右侧的更多可能性越来越多
make though the more possibilities on
the right-hand side more and more you
越来越接近左侧确定中的确切波动函数，所以现在我们
get closer and closer to the exact wave
function on on the left ok so now we
必须为此写出有效的较短方程
have to actually write down our
effective shorter equation for this
试用wavefunction，这实际上是您要做的功课
trial wavefunction and that's something
you're actually going to do for homework
我会写出答案，它看起来非常像一个较短的方程式
I'll write out the answer it's it looks
very much like a shorter equation it's
没有太多理由就可以相信的东西
something to probably believe without
too much justification it looks entirely
像一个更短的方程式，唯一的不同是这个HHIJ是2
like a shorter equation the only
difference is that this H H I J is a 2
乘2矩阵IHJI忘了告诉您一些我们假设我们说的内容
by 2 matrix I H J I forgot to tell you
something that we're assuming we put it
在这里，所以这是一个糟糕的假设糟糕的假设糟糕的假设是
over here so this is a bad assumption
bad assumption the bad assumption is
IJ是delta IJ，换句话说1/2等于零
that I J is delta IJ in other words 1/2
equals zero okay that one into
正交波函数现在是一个很好的近似
orthogonal wave functions now that's a
good approximation if the way if the
原子核相距很远，但是如果您将原子核真正靠近在一起，那不是
nuclei are far apart but if you put the
nuclei really close together it's no
再有一个好的假设，就是我们使这个糟糕的原因
longer a good assumption
the reason we're making this bad
假设是因为它使我们的生活更加轻松，并且在许多情况下
assumption is because it makes our life
a lot easier and as in many cases making
这个错误的假设不会丢掉关键的物理学，所以我们要
this bad assumption isn't going to throw
out the crucial physics so we're gonna
保持这个错误的假设，如果您想在书中进行练习
keep this bad assumption for now there's
an exercise in the book if you want to
通过它并更正确地进行操作，但是正确的关键物理
go through it and do it more properly
but you'll get the crucial physics right
通过做出这个错误的假设，我们将继续前进
by making this bad assumption so we're
gonna go ahead and do it
我相信上学期您这样做时并没有使用这个错误的假设
I believe when you did it last term you
did not use this bad assumption the
代数变得更糟，因此将尝试使代数保持简单
algebra gets much worse so it's going to
try to keep the algebra as simple as
假设这个错误的假设是
possible by making that bad assumption
given that bad assumption this is the
需要解决的薛定inger方程，它看起来很像一个
Schrodinger equation that you have to
solve and it looks pretty much like a
较短的方程式，您知道存在哈密顿波函数能量波
shorter equation you know there's a
Hamiltonian wavefunction energy wave
功能的唯一区别是，它不是完整的哈密顿量
function the only difference is it's not
the full Hamiltonians just the way the
哈密​​尔顿投影到我们的受限空间，其中仅包括波浪
hamiltonian projected to our restricted
space which includes only the wave
函数1和波动函数2，所以它是一个投影的缩短方程，例如
function 1 and the wave function 2 so
it's a projected shortener equation like
因此，要解决此问题，我们需要做的是2乘2
so to solve this all we need to do is we
need to come up with this is a 2 by 2
在我们的例子中，矩阵2乘2我们需要在这里写出矩阵元素
matrix 2 by 2 in our case we need to
write out the matrix elements here so
让我们做一个H 1是1 K加上V 1我还有汉密尔顿吗
let's do that one H 1 is 1 K plus V 1 do
I still have the Hamilton yeah the
哈密​​尔顿仍然在那儿，我希望它不会脱离常规
Hamiltonian is still up there I hope it
doesn't go off the board
1加1 V 2 1这个术语很容易，因为1 ket 1是k加V的本征态
1 plus 1 V 2 1 this term is easy because
1 the ket 1 is an eigenstate of k plus V
1这就是我们定义它的方式，因为特征值是epsilon，实际上不是这样
1 that's how we defined it and as
eigenvalue is epsilon not so in fact one
在一个是1上，您会发现它是一个这样的东西，这给我们
on one is 1 you can find it to be so
this pretty piece here just gives us
epsilon不是这部分，我们不知道那是什么，我将其称为V
epsilon not this part here we don't know
what that is I'm going to call it V
越过V越过物理上，我们有一个电子坐在轨道上
cross and physically what is it V cross
we have an electron sitting on orbital
一个在这里，所以这里是电子坐，这是轨道二，
one over here and so here's the electron
sitting and here's orbital two and
v-cross是电子之间的相互作用
v-cross
is the interaction between the electron
坐在一种状态，坐在一个核上，与两个核相互作用，这是
sitting on state one sitting on nucleus
one interacting with nucleus two that's
我相信上个名词你可能曾称呼过V-直接互动
what V crosses I believe last term you
may have called it - direct interaction
我可能已经说过，J从上学期开始听起来很耳熟吗？
I may have called it J does that sound
familiar from last term yeah okay the
我之所以不直接称其为J是因为在凝聚态下
reason I'm not calling it direct and J
is because in condensed matter those
单词用于某些不同的东西，我试图避免
words are used for something somewhat
different and I'm trying to avoid
对此感到困惑，所以我将其称为V形交叉，其中有些
confusion about that so I'm gonna call
it V cross instead and there's some
两把Naumann黏土椅子之间的关系，但不足以值得
relation between the two Naumann clay
chairs but not enough that it's worth
保持它这样扔掉，我们从现在起将其称为V交叉-H-我们
keeping it so throw that out we're gonna
call it V cross from now on - H - we
需要它也非常类似于K加B 2 2 + 1 2 V 1 2
need that also it's very similar to K
plus B 2 2 + 1 2 V 1 2 and again this
事情是ε零加V交叉，更有趣的是1 H 2这是
thing is epsilon naught plus V cross the
more interesting piece is 1 H 2 which is
1 K + V 2 2 + 1 V 1 2好的，所以这很容易，因为K + V 2
1 K plus V 2 2 + 1 V 1 2 okay so this
thing is easy actually because K + V 2
是epsilon naught 2，然后假设2 +1是正交的，所以得到0
is epsilon naught 2 and then 2 + 1 have
been assumed orthogonal so that gives 0
好吧，这大大简化了我们的生活，在这里我称之为跳车
okay so that's simplifies our life a lot
this one here I'm gonna call hopping
跳，通常称为-TI相信您去年致电交易所
hopping and generally it's called - T I
believe last year you call the exchange
我可能将其称为Kappa之类的东西，所以我不再使用
and I probably called it Kappa or
something so again I'm not going to use
那南围墙，因为我们现在用交换来交换其他东西，为什么
that Nam enclosure because we use a
exchange for something else now why does
如果您考虑与时间有关的薛定inger方程，就称其为跳跃
it call hopping if you think in terms of
the time-dependent schrodinger equation
这种对角线会使您从2变到1，所以
it's this kind of term that sort of off
diagonal takes you from 2 to 1 so a
跳变项可以给电子罐列表带来动力
hopping term can give dynamics to an
electron can list
拿起一个从两个原子核开始并着陆在一个原子核上的电子
take an electron that starts on nucleus
two and lands it on nucleus one so it
允许您从一个原子核跳到另一个原子核
allows you hop from one nucleus to the
other hence the name hopping reasonable
名字好吧，鉴于此，我们快到了
name okay so given this we're almost
there
我们有零乘两乘的哈密顿矩阵epsilon加V cross减
we have our two-by-two Hamiltonian
matrix epsilon naught plus V cross minus
t减去t如果它很复杂，它将在这里变成星星，然后epsilon
t minus t if it's if it's complex it
would get a t star here then epsilon
交叉是一个很好的厄米矩阵，我们可以对角化它
auspi the cross is a nice little
hermitian matrix we can diagonalize it
我们得到零的特征值heigl epsilon加V叉正负
we get the eigenvalues heigl epsilon
naught plus V cross plus or minus
T的绝对值，现在我留下一小块，现在放
absolute value of T now I left off one
little piece which I'm now going to put
回到我剩下的东西是inu清晰的核，你知道的能量
back in the thing I left off was the inu
clear nuclear that the energy you know
两个原子核也相互作用，所以如果我改变
the two nuclei are interacting with each
other as well so if I change the
两个原子核之间的距离会有库仑相互作用，但是
distance between the two nuclei they
would have some Coulomb interaction but
事实证明，核原子大约等于负V
it turns out that a nuclear nuclear is
very approximately equal to minus V
十字架，从您所了解的知识中，这实际上应该很明显
cross and that actually should be
obvious from what you know about
如果周围有球形电荷云，则产生静电
electrostatics if you have a spherical
charge cloud of charge around another
球形云电荷云可以考虑整体电荷云
spherical cloud charge of cloud of
charge you can considering the whole
电荷为原点，整个电荷为原点为零
charge as being at the origin and the
whole charge is that the origin is zero
e取消加号，减号1取消加号，所以最终这些
the e cancels the plus one the minus one
cancels plus one so this ends up these
两块彼此抵消，所以我只想写e正负两点
two pieces cancel each other so I'm just
going to write e plus or minus the two
可能的能量是Anat加上或减去绝对T，所以这就是X
possible energies are Anat plus or minus
absolute T so this is something that X
我们获得或获得或减少的能量数量似乎很自然
seems fairly natural that the amount of
gaining or lowering of the energy we get
当我们走时，当我们允许电子在两个轨道之间跳跃时，由
when we go when we allow the electron to
hop between the two orbitals is given by
我们通过散布电子波函数让他们跳多少
how much we allow them to hop so by
spreading out the electron wave function
您降低它的能量，您越分散波函数，您越降低
you lower its energy the more you spread
out the wave function the more you lower
能量，所以我们甚至可以在这里做，是的，我们甚至可以写下两个
the energy um so we can even maybe do it
here yeah we can even write down the two
如果将矩阵定义为对角化，则其本征态
eigenstates of this if you diagonalize
that that matrix is defined its eigen
向量，您会发现该边加1
vectors
you would find that side plus 1 over
根2 1加oops 1减2这是反键高能反键
root 2 1 plus oops 1 minus 2 this is the
antibonding the higher energy anti bond
较高的能量波函数，然后较低的能量波函数1 over
the higher energy wave function and then
the lower energy wave function 1 over
根2 1加2，实际上wave函数的那些形式应该看起来很多
root 2 1 plus 2 and in fact those forms
of the wave function should look a lot
就像我们在盒子中的粒子中所拥有的一样，在粒子中，但是在盒子中我们拥有
like what we had in the particle in the
box so in particle but in the box we had
这里有一个键合轨道键，我们这里有一个反键轨道
a bonding orbital bond here and we have
an antibonding orbital here and e here
中间有一个节点，现在我们有两个原子核键合轨道
with a node in the middle and now we
have two nuclei the bonding orbital
看起来像是对称的键，而反键看起来像这样
looks like this it's symmetric a bond
bond and the anti bond looks like this
加抗粘结，所以它与粒子中的粒子非常相似
plus plus antibonding so it's very
similar to what we have in the particle
在两种情况下的方框中，节点的存在都会提高能量
in the box in both cases the existence
of the node raises the energy ok
因此，您获得或失去的能量取决于跳跃的数量
so since the amount of energy you gain
or lose depends on the amount of hopping
作为R 1减去R 2的函数，您可能会
as a function of R 1 minus R 2 the
distance between the nuclei you might
当您将两个原子核放得更近时，期望跳跃会增加
expect that the hopping goes up as you
put the two nuclei closer together so
您会期望防粘结看起来像这样，粘结看起来像
you would expect that the antibonding
looks like this the bonding looks like
这或多或少是对的，但实际上更准确是
this and that's more or less right but
actually more accurate is something that
e R 1减R 2看起来像这样
looks like this e R 1 minus R 2
antibonding goes like this and bonding
当两个原子核彼此靠得太近，以至于所有
goes like this again when the two nuclei
get too close together that all of a
突然变得非常排斥，而变得排斥的原因是
sudden becomes extremely repulsive and
the reason it becomes repulsive is
因为我们的许多近似都分解了这个近似分解
because a lot of our approximations
break down this approximation breaks
下来，两个原子轨道正在使用的两个核不再
down that the two nuclear the two atomic
orbitals were using are no longer
正交的，进一步说，我就两个电荷做出了陈述
orthogonal and further that statement I
made up there about the two charge
一旦正电荷进入另一个云层，云消除就会分解
clouds canceling breaks down once the
positive charge gets inside the other
一旦其他原子核获得，您就会知道电子
electrons
you know once the other nucleus gets
在电子的电荷云中，那么您将无法再取消您
inside the charge cloud of the electron
then you can no longer cancel you
记住这条规则，如果您在某些收费之内，则不算，如果
remember this rule that if you're inside
some charge you don't count it and if
如果您在谈论球形的时候算了算，那么您就不在费用之列
you're outside the charge if you count
it when you're talking about a spherical
电荷分配，将您体内的任何东西都靠近中心
charge distribution anything that's
inside you closer to the center you
数，然后将所有内容置于中心，而您认为之外的所有内容
count and you put all the at the center
and anything is outside you think you
扔掉，所以如果原子核进入电子的电荷云，那么它
throw away so if the nucleus gets inside
the charge cloud of the electron then it
开始看到另一个核，并开始被另一个核排斥
starts to see the other nucleus and it
starts to be repelled by the other
原子核，所以键的能量上升了，这里的另一件事
nucleus so the energy of the bond goes
goes way up one more thing here before
如果我们有两个，我们在结束之前也可以考虑一个非常相似的物理学
we before we end you can also consider a
very similar physics if you have two
不同的原子，所以我们有氢和氟，在这里我画了一个
different atoms so we have hydrogen and
fluorine and here I've drawn one up here
还有一个在这里，因为如果你在氢上有一个电子，它们的能量
and one down here because their energies
if you just have an electron on hydrogen
它的能量比氟上的电子高得多，哦，也许我应该
it's much higher energy than the
electron on fluorine oh maybe I should
曾经说过氟中的钠和氟钠没关系，只是你知道
have said sodium and fluorine sodium in
the florium doesn't matter just you know
在低电离能或想要少得多的电子的物体上
on something that has a low ionization
energy or wants the electron a lot less
还有电子亲和力高或组织性高的东西
and something with a high electron
affinity or a high organization and she
想要更多电子，您可以允许电子离域
wants the electron a lot more and you
can allow an electron to delocalized
如果这样做的话，钠和氟之间会发生变化
between the sodium and the fluorine if
you do that the only thing that changes
这是对角线上的这两个能量变成e钠和氟
here is that these two energies on the
diagonal become e sodium and a fluorine
这样好，那两个可以彼此不同
like that okay and those two can be
different from each other
如果将这个矩阵对角化，现在您将再次找到两个不同的能量
if you diagonalize this matrix now
you'll find two different energies again
所以我们把它画成一个结合和反结合的轨道
so we'll draw that as a bonding and
antibonding orbital
所以这里又有一个反键，使电子返回并
so there's antibonding down here again
allowing the electron to go back and
第四改变了总能量，这里是反键，但是这些
forth changes the total energy and
here's antibonding up here but these
系数将与反粘结轨道的系数不同
coefficients will not be the same that
for the antibonding orbital this this
系数处于-alpha将更大beta将大于alpha
coefficient being in - alpha will be
bigger beta would be bigger than alpha
电子更有可能越过这里
there'll be a higher probability that
the electron will be over here for the
反结合轨道，而对于像这样的结合轨道beta alpha，
antibonding orbital whereas for the
bonding orbital beta alpha like this the
波函数的最大权重将在此处
the most of the weight of the
wavefunction will be over here on
氟，这是一个简单的二乘二矩阵对角化问题
fluorine it's sort of a simple two by
two matrix diagonalization problem
这本书中也有一个练习，所以这个想法是，但是
there's an exercise in the book on this
as well so the idea is that but just by
看看这个二乘二的矩阵，您可以看到如何从共价键形成
looking at this two-by-two matrix you
can see how you go from a covalent bond
电子在两个原子核之间均等分布
where the electron is distributed
equally between the two the two nuclei
离子键，我们实际上是较低能量的轨道，使电子几乎
to an ionic bond we're really the lower
energy orbital puts the electron almost
完全在这里讨论低能物种，好吧，我想我停了下来
entirely over here on on the lower
energy species okay I guess I stopped
在那里，我明天见[鼓掌]
there and I see you tomorrow
[Applause]